<bill session="112" type="h" number="1148" updated="2011-06-04T06:14:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit commodities and securities trading based on nonpublic information relating to Congress, to require additional reporting by Members and employees of Congress of securities transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412214"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2011-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2011-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412254" joined="2011-04-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, House Administration, the Judiciary, and Ethics, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-17"><text>Referred to House Ethics</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T19:46:00-04:00"><text>RE-REFERRAL - Mr. Bachus asked unanimous consent that H.R. 1148 be re-referred primarily to the Committee on Financial Services and additionally to the Committees on Agriculture, House Administration, the Judiciary, Ethics and Rules. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T20:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T20:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T20:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee on House Administration discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T20:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29T20:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Ethics discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Rereferred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, House Administration, the Judiciary, Ethics, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House Ethics</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-29"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, Re-referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Re-referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities and Risk Management" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Re-referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Re-referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Ethics" activity="Referral, Re-referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Re-referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
		<term name="Securities"/>
		<term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2011--Introduced.
Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Commodity Exchange Act to direct both the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to prohibit purchase or sale of either securities, security-based swaps, or commodities for future delivery or swap by a person in possession of material nonpublic information regarding pending or prospective legislative action if the information was obtained: (1) knowingly from a Member or employee of Congress, (2) by reason of being a Member or employee of Congress, and (3) other federal employees. Amends the Code of Official Conduct of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit certain House personnel from disclosing material nonpublic information relating to any pending or prospective legislative action relating to either securities of a publicly-traded company or a commodity if such personnel has reason to believe that the information will be used to buy or sell the securities or commodity based on such information. Directs both the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives to hold hearings on the implementation by the CFTC and the SEC of such financial transaction prohibitions. Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require formal disclosure of certain securities and commodities futures transactions to either the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to subject to its registration, reporting, and disclosure requirements, as well as requirements for identification of clients and covered legislative and executive officials, all political intelligence activities, contacts, firms, and consultants. Requires the Comptroller General to include political intelligence activities, contacts, firms, and consultants in its annual compliance audits and reports.

	</summary>
</bill>
