<bill session="112" type="h" number="1408" updated="2011-05-27T06:15:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization and Jobs Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412403" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412312" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412306" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412293" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412436" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412418" joined="2011-04-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-12"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Alaska Native Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="730" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Forests"/>
		<term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
		<term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
		<term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/6/2011--Introduced.
Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization and Jobs Protection Act - Authorizes Sealaska, the regional Alaska Native Corporation for southeast Alaska, subject to certain conditions and restrictions, to select and receive conveyance of its remaining land entitlement under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) from federal land in southeast Alaska that is outside the areas for selection delineated by the ANCSA. Includes in these lands certain sites: (1) identified on specified maps as having traditional and recreational use value; and (2) identified by Sealaska as having sacred, cultural, traditional, or historic significance. Prohibits Sealaska from selecting: (1) sacred, cultural, traditional, or historic sites that are within the National Park System; or (2) land from the mapped sites, other than trade and migration route land, that lies within a conservation system unit, federally designated wilderness area, or certain land use designation areas.
Authorizes the Director of the National Park Service to enter into a cooperative management agreement with Sealaska, other Village Corporations and Urban Corporations, and federally recognized Indian tribes with cultural and historical ties to Glacier Bay National Park to recognize and perpetuate National Park Service values, including those associated with the Tlingit homeland and culture, wilderness, and ecological preservation.

	</summary>
</bill>
