<bill session="112" type="h" number="1410" updated="2011-05-14T06:15:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote freedom and democracy in Vietnam.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2011-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2011-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2011-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2011-04-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-13"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-13"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Africa, Global Health, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Human trafficking"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Military assistance and sales, agreements, alliances"/>
		<term name="News media and reporting"/>
		<term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
		<term name="Political representation"/>
		<term name="Property rights"/>
		<term name="Protest and dissent"/>
		<term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
		<term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Sanctions"/>
		<term name="Vietnam"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/7/2011--Introduced.
Vietnam Human Rights Act of 2011 - Prohibits U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance to the government of Vietnam in excess of FY2011 amounts unless: (1) the federal government provides assistance, in addition to democracy building assistance under this Act, supporting human rights training, civil society building, and exchange programs between the Vietnamese National Assembly and Congress at levels commensurate with or exceeding any increases in nonhumanitarian assistance to Vietnam; and (2) the President certifies to Congress that the government of Vietnam has made substantial progress respecting political, media, and religious freedoms, minority rights, access to U.S. refugee programs, and actions to end trafficking in persons and the release of political prisoners. Authorizes the President to waive such requirements if increased U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance would promote the purposes of this Act or is otherwise in the U.S. national interest. Authorizes the President to provide U.S. assistance through appropriate nongovernmental organizations and the Human Rights Defenders Fund for the support of individuals and organizations to promote human rights in Vietnam. Declares it is U.S. policy: (1) to take measures to overcome the jamming of Radio Free Asia by the government of Vietnam, and (2) that educational and cultural exchange programs with Vietnam should promote progress toward democracy. Declares it is U.S. policy to offer refugee resettlement to Vietnam nationals (including members of the Montagnard ethnic minority groups) who were eligible for the Humanitarian Resettlement program, the Orderly Departure program, the Resettlement Opportunities for Vietnamese Returnees program, the Amerasian Homecoming Act of 1988, or any other U.S. refugee program, but who were deemed ineligible for reasons of administrative error or who failed to apply because of circumstances beyond their control. Sets forth reporting requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
