<bill session="112" type="h" number="1540" updated="2011-06-07T06:10:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="375"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2012 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2012 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400267"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2011-04-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-11"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 60 - 1.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-11T12:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Reed asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services have until 5:00 p.m. on May 17 to file a report on H.R. 1540. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-17T16:50:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 112-78.</text></action>
		<calendar number="39" datetime="2011-05-17T16:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to file a supplemental report on H.R. 1540. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:11:00-04:00"><text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 112-78, Part II.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T18:44:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 269 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1216 and H.R. 1540. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate and waives all points of order against consideration of the measures. The rule provides one motion to recommit H.R. 1216 with or without instructions. The rule also provides that after general debate on H.R. 1540, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion and that no further consideration of the bill shall occur except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T14:39:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 269 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T18:48:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 269.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3388-3396"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T18:48:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1216 and H.R. 1540. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides for 1 hour of general debate and waives all points of order against consideration of the measures. The rule provides one motion to recommit H.R. 1216 with or without instructions. The rule also provides that after general debate on H.R. 1540, the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion and that no further consideration of the bill shall occur except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T18:48:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 269 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T18:48:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Womack to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T18:48:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1540.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T19:58:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1540 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24T21:30:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 276 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1540. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Armed Services now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:01:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 276 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3436-3621"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:03:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wittman amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Woolsey amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:21:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Woolsey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #1 amendments as modified.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:38:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carter amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T15:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hunter amendment no. 12.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:00:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hunter amendment no. 12, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith(WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:01:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carson amendment no. 19.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #2 amendments as modified.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sarbanes amendment no. 24.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:27:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sarbanes amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sarbanes demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:28:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy(CT) amendment no. 25.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:36:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Murphy(CT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Murphy(CT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cole amendment no. 27.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:46:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cole amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cummings demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment no. 28.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:58:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garamendi demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:59:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McKeon moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:59:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T16:59:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1540 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3621-3630, H3630-3643"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:01:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Maloney amendment no. 26.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:11:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Maloney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Maloney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Himes amendment no. 30.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:21:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Himes amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Forbes demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee(TX) amendment no. 31.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:30:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee(TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee(TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Andrews amendment no. 32.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:38:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Andrews amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Andrews demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lee amendment no. 33.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Richmond amendment no. 37.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:55:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Richmond amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Richmond demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T17:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mica amendment no. 38.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T18:02:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mica amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Mica demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T18:04:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T19:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment no. 39.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T19:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment no. 40.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T19:33:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Critz demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T19:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schakowsky amendment no. 41.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T19:43:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:07:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buchanan amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:16:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Buchanan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Buchanan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Maloney (NY) amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:24:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Maloney (NY) amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Maloney (NY) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:25:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mack amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:31:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mack amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Andrews demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Mack amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:41:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Langevin amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Langevin demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T20:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Amash amendment, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:08:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McKeon demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Campbell amendment No. 53.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:19:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment No. 53, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Campbell amendment No. 54.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:29:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment No. 54, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chaffetz amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:43:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Chaffetz amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Chaffetz demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rohrabacher amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T21:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:08:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conyers amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:17:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Conyers amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Conyers demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:30:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment No. 62, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:43:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendent and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Loretta Sanchez (CA) amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:56:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Loretta Sanchez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Sanchez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T22:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Edwards amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T23:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McKeon moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T23:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25T23:05:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1540 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:15:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3687-3737"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:15:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 1540 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to H.Res. 276, amendment no. 55 be considered out of sequence. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:16:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Inslee amendment no. 110.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment no. 111.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:28:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendent and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Runyan amendment no. 134.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Thompson (PA) amendment no. 141.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner amendment no. 148.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:48:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Turner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendent and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Roby demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T10:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cravaak amendment no. 152.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T11:01:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cravaack amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendent and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T11:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McGovern amendment no. 55, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T11:34:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McGovern amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T11:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #3 amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T11:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #4 amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T12:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #5 amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T12:16:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the McKeon en bloc #6 amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:04:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1540.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:05:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union. (text: CR 5/25/2011 H3436-3595)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Schrader moved to recommit with instructions to Armed Services.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3735-3737"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H3735"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrader motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to increase the maximum amount of special pay for Combat Troops subject to hostile fire or imminent danger to $325 per month. The increase in pay will take effect on October 1, 2011 and apply to months beginning on or after that date.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:13:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3736"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:32:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 185 - 233 (Roll no. 374).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="375" datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 322 - 96 (Roll no. 375).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T14:39:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1540.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="269" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="276" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="981" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Afghanistan"/>
		<term name="Alliances"/>
		<term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Defense spending"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Military assistance and sales, agreements, alliances"/>
		<term name="Military civil functions"/>
		<term name="Military education and training"/>
		<term name="Military facilities and property"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
		<term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
		<term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
		<term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
		<term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
		<term name="Transportation costs"/>
		<term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
		<term name="Wages and earnings"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h301"/>
		<amendment number="h302"/>
		<amendment number="h303"/>
		<amendment number="h304"/>
		<amendment number="h305"/>
		<amendment number="h306"/>
		<amendment number="h307"/>
		<amendment number="h308"/>
		<amendment number="h309"/>
		<amendment number="h310"/>
		<amendment number="h311"/>
		<amendment number="h312"/>
		<amendment number="h313"/>
		<amendment number="h314"/>
		<amendment number="h315"/>
		<amendment number="h316"/>
		<amendment number="h317"/>
		<amendment number="h318"/>
		<amendment number="h319"/>
		<amendment number="h320"/>
		<amendment number="h321"/>
		<amendment number="h322"/>
		<amendment number="h323"/>
		<amendment number="h324"/>
		<amendment number="h325"/>
		<amendment number="h326"/>
		<amendment number="h327"/>
		<amendment number="h328"/>
		<amendment number="h329"/>
		<amendment number="h330"/>
		<amendment number="h331"/>
		<amendment number="h332"/>
		<amendment number="h333"/>
		<amendment number="h334"/>
		<amendment number="h335"/>
		<amendment number="h336"/>
		<amendment number="h337"/>
		<amendment number="h338"/>
		<amendment number="h339"/>
		<amendment number="h340"/>
		<amendment number="h341"/>
		<amendment number="h342"/>
		<amendment number="h343"/>
		<amendment number="h344"/>
		<amendment number="h345"/>
		<amendment number="h346"/>
		<amendment number="h347"/>
		<amendment number="h348"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/2011--Introduced.
National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 - Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2012 for: (1) procurement, including for aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, and shipbuilding and conversion; (2) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (3) research, development, test, and evaluation; (4) operation and maintenance; (5) military personnel; (6) Working Capital Funds; (7) the National Defense Sealift Fund; (8) the Joint Urgent Operational Needs Fund; (9) chemical agents and munitions destruction; (10) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; (11) the Defense Inspector General; (12) the Defense Health Program; (13) the Armed Forces Retirement Home; (14) overseas contingency operations; (15) chemical demilitarization; (16) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (17) National Guard and reserve forces facilities; and (18) military base closure and realignment activities. Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2012 for military construction, military family housing, and energy conservation projects. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning: (1) military personnel policy; (2) education and training; (3) military pay and allowances; (4) acquisition policy and management; (5) DOD organization and management; (6) civilian personnel; and (7) matters relating to foreign nations.

	</summary>
</bill>
