<bill session="112" type="h" number="1627" updated="2011-05-25T06:16:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-23T18:54:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="2011-05-23T18:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="330"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Honoring American Veterans Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for certain requirements for the placement of monuments in Arlington National Cemetery, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400279"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412460" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412310" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2011-04-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-15"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-15"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-29"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-03"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-05"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-05"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-12"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-12"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-18"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-20T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 112-84, Part I. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-20T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="45" datetime="2011-05-20T12:13:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 45.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Miller (FL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:10:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3310-3313"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:10:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1627.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T16:28:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T18:32:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3319-3320"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="330" datetime="2011-05-23T18:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 380 - 0 (Roll no. 330).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3310-3311"/></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-05-23T18:54:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Military cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2011--Introduced.
Allows a monument other than one containing or marking interred remains (monument) to be placed in Arlington National Cemetery (Arlington) only if the monument commemorates: (1) the military service of the individual or group whose memory is honored by the monument, or (2) a particular military event. Prohibits any monument from being placed in Arlington until the end of the 25-year period beginning on the last day of the service or event commemorated. Allows a monument to be placed only in those sections of Arlington designated by the Secretary of the Army and only on land determined by the Secretary as unsuitable for burial. Allows a monument to be placed in Arlington only if an appropriate non-governmental entity has agreed to act as a sponsoring organization to coordinate the monument's placement and: (1) monument construction and placement are paid for using only private funds, (2) the Secretary consults with the Commission of Fine Arts before approving the monument's design, and (3) the sponsoring organization provides for an independent study on the availability and suitability of alternative monument locations outside of Arlington. Authorizes the Secretary to waive the 25-year requirement, above, when the monument would commemorate a group of individuals who the Secretary determines: (1) has made valuable contributions to the Armed Forces that have been ongoing and perpetual for longer than 25 years and are expected to continue indefinitely, and (2) has provided service that is of such a character that failure to place a monument to the group in Arlington would present a manifest injustice.

	</summary>
</bill>
