<bill session="112" type="h" number="1620" updated="2011-05-14T06:23:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve Federal land management, resource conservation, environmental protection, and use of Federal real property, by requiring the Secretary of the Interior to develop a multipurpose cadastre of Federal real property and identifying inaccurate, duplicate, and out-of-date Federal land inventories, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400218"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412271" joined="2011-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412272" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412270" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412294" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2011-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2011-04-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
		<term name="State and local finance"/>
		<term name="State and local government operations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2011--Introduced.
Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to develop a multipurpose cadastre of federal real property (an inventory of real property of the federal government) to assist with federal land management, resource conservation, environmental protection, and use of real property. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cost-sharing agreements with states to include any non-federal lands in a state in such cadastre. Limits the federal share of any such agreement to 50% of the total cost to a state for the development of the cadastre of the non-federal lands in the state. Requires the Secretary to submit a report on: (1) existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre, (2) consolidation of inventories and components, (3) the use of existing inventories and components of any cadastre, (4) the cost savings that will be achieved, and (4) recommendations for legislation.

	</summary>
</bill>
