<bill session="112" type="h" number="2017" updated="2011-06-11T06:23:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="409"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400004"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26T19:00:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-91, by Mr. Aderholt.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-26T19:01:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 50.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-31T20:00:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 287 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2017 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived except for section 536. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:25:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 287 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 287.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3832-3867"/><reference label="text of Title I as reported in House" ref="CR H3837, H3844, H3851-3852"/><reference label="text of Title II as reported in House" ref="CR H3856, H3857, H3857-3858, H3858-3860"/><reference label="text of Title III as reported in House" ref="CR H3861-3862, H3879, H3881, H3882"/><reference label="text of Title IV as reported in House" ref="CR H3882, H3883-3884"/><reference label="text of Title V as reported in House" ref="CR H3884-3885, H3886-3888"/><reference label="text of Title VI as reported in House" ref="CR H3890"/><reference label="text of Title VII as reported in House" ref="CR H3890"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2017 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived except for section 536. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 287 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:34:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David Dreier to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T15:35:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2017.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:16:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 287, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on pro forma amendments to H.R. 2017.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LaTourette amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:46:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaTourette amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cicilline amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:58:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cicilline amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Aderholt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T16:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Royce amendment number 2 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:07:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Royce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Royce demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee(TX) amendment number 12 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Broun(GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe(TX) amendment number 8 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:29:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Poe(TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Poe(TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Norton amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe(TX) amendment number 7 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:50:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:54:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T17:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:00:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:04:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cuellar amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:07:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cuellar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:07:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:55:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3855-3867"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T18:58:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King(IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King(IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Barrow amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:36:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T20:22:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clarke(MI) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Clarke (MI) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T20:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Heck amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T20:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Heck amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T20:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richardson amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T20:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Honda amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sessions amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:18:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sessions amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lummis amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:45:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carter amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richmond amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T21:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Carter amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:05:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carter amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment no. 9 under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment no. 10 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Richmond amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Poe amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price (NC) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:32:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price (NC) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scalise amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sherman amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:45:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sherman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sherman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gosar amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:55:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price(NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Altmire amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T22:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Scalise amendment under the five-minute rule. A point of order was reserved, but was subsequently removed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:12:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scalise amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Engel amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:48:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cravaack amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:53:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cravaack amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cravaack demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:57:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Amash demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T23:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:01:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:01:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:08:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Price (NC) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rokita amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:19:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rokita amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rokita demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rokita amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:27:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rokita amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rokita demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:27:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:28:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T00:28:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3928-3936"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:24:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Baldwin amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Speier amendment no. 19 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Speier amendment no. 18 under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:41:00-04:00"><text>Debate - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T12:53:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T13:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Aderholt moved to that the Committee now rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T13:51:00-04:00"><text>On motion to that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T13:52:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:26:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3939-3945"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:26:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:28:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Cole (OK) amendment No. 42 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:35:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cole (OK) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cole (OK) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gohmert amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:45:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gohmert amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gohmert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Issa amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T15:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Mica amendment under the five-minute rule, pending a reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the point of order was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T15:18:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mica amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Mica demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Aderholt moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T15:19:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2017 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T16:12:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3945-3964"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T16:12:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T16:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Polis(CO) amendment number 23 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T16:49:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis(CO) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis(CO) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T16:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Eshoo amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T17:06:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of adoption of amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Aderholt moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00"><text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:21:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2017.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:22:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3961"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:22:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bishop (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3961-3962"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H3962"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to increase grants for Transportation Security and Counterterrorism through offsets from the Department of Homeland Security's National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:31:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3962"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:52:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 234 (Roll no. 408).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="409" datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 188 (Roll no. 409).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T18:58:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="287" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Aviation and airports"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Coast guard"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Cuba"/>
		<term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
		<term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
		<term name="Fires"/>
		<term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
		<term name="Foreign labor"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Homeland security"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Military facilities and property"/>
		<term name="Prescription drugs"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Trade restrictions"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h349"/>
		<amendment number="h350"/>
		<amendment number="h351"/>
		<amendment number="h352"/>
		<amendment number="h353"/>
		<amendment number="h354"/>
		<amendment number="h355"/>
		<amendment number="h356"/>
		<amendment number="h357"/>
		<amendment number="h358"/>
		<amendment number="h359"/>
		<amendment number="h360"/>
		<amendment number="h361"/>
		<amendment number="h362"/>
		<amendment number="h363"/>
		<amendment number="h364"/>
		<amendment number="h365"/>
		<amendment number="h366"/>
		<amendment number="h367"/>
		<amendment number="h368"/>
		<amendment number="h369"/>
		<amendment number="h370"/>
		<amendment number="h371"/>
		<amendment number="h372"/>
		<amendment number="h373"/>
		<amendment number="h374"/>
		<amendment number="h375"/>
		<amendment number="h376"/>
		<amendment number="h377"/>
		<amendment number="h378"/>
		<amendment number="h379"/>
		<amendment number="h380"/>
		<amendment number="h381"/>
		<amendment number="h382"/>
		<amendment number="h383"/>
		<amendment number="h384"/>
		<amendment number="h385"/>
		<amendment number="h386"/>
		<amendment number="h387"/>
		<amendment number="h388"/>
		<amendment number="h389"/>
		<amendment number="h390"/>
		<amendment number="h391"/>
		<amendment number="h392"/>
		<amendment number="h393"/>
		<amendment number="h394"/>
		<amendment number="h395"/>
		<amendment number="h396"/>
		<amendment number="h397"/>
		<amendment number="h398"/>
		<amendment number="h399"/>
		<amendment number="h400"/>
		<amendment number="h401"/>
		<amendment number="h402"/>
		<amendment number="h403"/>
		<amendment number="h404"/>
		<amendment number="h405"/>
		<amendment number="h406"/>
		<amendment number="h407"/>
		<amendment number="h408"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/2011--Introduced.
Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012 - Makes appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY2012 for: (1) the Offices of the Secretary, the Under Secretary for Management, the Chief Financial Officer, the Chief Information Officer, and the Inspector General; (2) United States Customs and Border Protection (CBP); (3) United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE); (4) the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), including for civil aviation security services, service transportation security activities, the development and implementation of screening programs of the Office of Transportation Threat Assessment and Credentialing, transportation security support and intelligence, and the Federal Air Marshals; (5) the Coast Guard; (6) the United States Secret Service; (7) the Office of the Under Secretary for National Protection and Programs Directorate, including for the Federal Protective Service and the U.S. Visitor and Immigrant Status Indicator Technology (U.S.-VISIT) project; (8) the Office of Health Affairs; (9) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), including for firefighter assistance grants, emergency management performance grants, and the United States Fire Administration; (10) United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (CIS), including for the E-Verify program to assist U.S. employers maintain a legal workforce; (11) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center; (12) the Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology; and (13) the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act: (1) to amend the oath of allegiance required under the Immigration and Nationality Act; (2) to prevent an individual not in the business of importing a prescription drug from importing a prescription drug from Canada that complies with the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act for personal use; (3) for planning, testing, piloting, or developing a national identification card; or (4) to transfer or release to or within the United States Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the U.S. Armed Forces and who is or was held on or after June 24, 2009, at the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, by the Department of Defense (DOD). Requires: (1) the FEMA Administrator to submit to Congress, and publish on the FEMA website, a report summarizing damage assessment information used to make a declaration that a major disaster exists, with a national security limitation; and (2) the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security to submit a report that certifies that a requirement for 100% screening air cargo on passenger aircraft has been met or that includes a strategy to comply with that requirement.

	</summary>
</bill>
