<bill session="112" type="h" number="2055" updated="2011-06-14T06:19:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-31T14:13:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-05-31T14:13:00-04:00" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-05-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400089"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-05-31T14:05:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 112-94, by Mr. Culberson.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-31T14:13:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-06-01T19:06:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 288 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2055 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T14:26:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 288 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 288.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3964-3977"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H3969-3976"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:01:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2055 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. Points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 of rule XXI are waived. The resolution authorizes the Chair to accord priority in recognition to Members who have pre-printed their amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:01:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 288 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:01:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:01:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2055.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T19:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 288, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Culberson amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T20:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Culberson moved that the Committee now rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T20:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-02T20:01:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2055 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:12:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:14:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Mica amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the LaTourette amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:55:00-04:00"><text>POSPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaTourette amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Culberson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T14:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Meeks amendment number 1 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:07:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment number 4 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:26:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amash amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Culberson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sherman amendment number 2 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:36:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sherman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Dicks demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Amash amendment number 5 under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:40:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Flores amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Coffman (CO) amendment under the five-minute rule, pending the reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T15:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Fitzpatrick amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T16:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Culberson moved that the Committee now rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T16:12:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T16:12:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2055 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T18:29:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T18:30:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T19:07:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2055.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T19:08:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T19:08:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T19:09:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to section 2(a) of House Resolution 288, the Chair put the question on retaining Title II (relating to Veterans' Affairs) of the bill and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded a recorded vote to decide the question.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-06-13T19:25:00-04:00"><text>On retaining Title II (Department of Veterans Affairs) Agreed to by recorded vote: 409 - 1 (Roll no. 416).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="288" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h409"/>
		<amendment number="h410"/>
		<amendment number="h411"/>
		<amendment number="h412"/>
		<amendment number="h413"/>
		<amendment number="h414"/>
		<amendment number="h415"/>
		<amendment number="h416"/>
		<amendment number="h417"/>
		<amendment number="h418"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/31/2011--Introduced.
Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012 - Appropriates funds for FY2012 for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military construction for the Army, Navy and Marine Corps, and Air Force (military departments), DOD, the Army and Air National Guard, and the Army, Navy, and Air Force reserves; (2) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (3) family housing construction and related operation and maintenance for the military departments and DOD; (4) the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund; (5) the Homeowners Assistance Fund; (6) DOD chemical demilitarization construction; and (7) the Department of Defense Base Closure Accounts of 1990 and 2005. Appropriates funds for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration; (2) readjustment benefits; (3) veterans insurance and indemnities; (4) the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund; (5) the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program; (6) the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program; (7) the Veterans Health Administration; (8) the National Cemetery Administration; (9) the Office of Inspector General; (10) construction for major and minor projects; and (11) grants for the construction of extended care facilities and veterans cemeteries. Appropriates funds for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (3) DOD cemeterial expenses; and (4) the Armed Forces Retirement Home. Specifies restrictions and authorities regarding the use of funds appropriated in this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
