<bill session="112" type="h" number="222" updated="2011-02-05T06:12:31-05:00">
	<state datetime="2011-01-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Infant Protection and Baby Switching Prevention Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals reimbursed under the Medicare system to establish and implement security procedures to reduce the likelihood of infant patient abduction and baby switching, including procedures for identifying all infant patients in the hospital in a manner that ensures that it will be evident if infants are missing from the hospital.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-07"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-07"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-07"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-24"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Crimes against children"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Violent crime"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2011--Introduced.
Infant Protection and Baby Switching Prevention Act of 2011 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require certain hospitals reimbursed under Medicare, which also provide neonatal and infant care, to have in effect security procedures to reduce the likelihood of infant patient abduction and baby switching, including procedures for identifying all infant patients in the hospital in a manner that ensures that it will be evident if infants are missing. Establishes civil penalties for failure to have such security procedures in effect.
Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit and establish criminal penalties for baby switching in hospitals.

	</summary>
</bill>
