<bill session="112" type="h" number="33" updated="2011-05-07T06:10:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to specify when certain securities issued in connection with church plans are treated as exempted securities for purposes of that Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400027"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Financial Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Securities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2011--Introduced.
Amends the Securities Act of 1933 with respect to when certain securities issued in connection with retirement income accounts available only to certain kinds of church plans are treated as exempted from registration and disclosure requirements under such Act (exempted securities). Revises exclusions from the meaning of exempted securities to add as an exempted security a certain kind of retirement income account (available only to church plans), to the extent that the interest or participation in a single trust fund or collective trust fund (e.g. a &quot;stable value fund&quot;) is issued to: (1) a church, a convention or association of churches, or a specified kind of organization (including a church pension board established to maintain employee benefit programs) which establishes or maintains the retirement income account; or (2) a trust established by any such entity in connection with the retirement income account. Revises a further such exclusion from exempted security treatment of plans whose participants may include persons (in particular clergymen) who may be considered self-employed for certain tax purposes. Allows exempted security treatment of such plans. (In effect, an exemption from registration and related requirements is granted to collective trust funds that are invested in by kinds of church plans currently excluded from making such investments.)

	</summary>
</bill>
