<bill session="112" type="h" number="441" updated="2011-05-06T06:12:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-01-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2010</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits for a microhydro project in nonwilderness areas within the boundaries of Denali National Park and Preserve, to acquire land for Denali National Park and Preserve from Doyon Tourism, Inc., and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="313" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Dams and canals"/>
		<term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/25/2011--Introduced.
Kantishna Hills Renewable Energy Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits for a specified microhydro project in the Kantishna Hills area within the Denali National Park and Preserve in Alaska. Defines &quot;microhydro project&quot; as a hydroelectric power generating facility with a maximum power generation capability of 100 kilowatts and includes any distribution or transmission line required to serve such area. Directs the Secretary to exchange Park and Preserve land near or adjacent to land owned by Doyon Tourism, Inc., located at the mouth of Eureka Creek for approximately 18 acres of land owned by Doyon Tourism within the Galena patented mining claim. Requires the land acquired by the Secretary to be administered as part of the Park and Preserve. 
	</summary>
</bill>
