<bill session="112" type="h" number="46" updated="2011-01-25T06:16:48-05:00">
	<state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fallen Heroes Family Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for nonimmigrant status for an alien who is the parent or legal guardian of a United States citizen child if the child was born abroad and is the child of a deceased member of the Armed Forces of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400196"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-24"><committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Family relationships"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
		<term name="Visas and passports"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2011--Introduced.
Fallen Heroes Family Act of 2011 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include as a nonimmigrant alien an alien who is the parent of a child who: (1) is a U.S. citizen; (2) was born outside the United States and its outlying possessions; and (3) had a natural parent who served honorably in an active-duty status in the U.S. Armed Forces and died on or after September 11, 2001, from an injury or disease incurred in or aggravated by that service. Defines &quot;parent&quot; to include a legal guardian or other person standing in loco parentis for purposes of: (1) such nonimmigrant alien; and (2) immediate relative status with respect to aliens who are not subject to direct numerical limitations. Sets forth related conditions concerning: (1) employment; (2) period of authorized admission; and (3) number of aliens to be admitted for each such child.

	</summary>
</bill>
