<bill session="112" type="h" number="461" updated="2011-02-15T06:13:44-05:00">
	<state datetime="2011-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal features of the electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412270"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2011-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2011--Introduced.
South Utah Valley Electric Conveyance Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, insofar as the Strawberry Water Users Association conveyed its interest in an electric distribution system to the South Utah Valley Electric Service District, to convey and assign to the District: (1) all interest of the United States in all fixtures owned by the United States as part of the electric distribution system and the federal lands and interests where the fixtures are located, (2) license for use in perpetuity of the shared power poles, and (3) licenses for use and access in perpetuity to specified project lands and interests and corridors where federal lands and interests are abutting public streets and roads and can provide access to facilities.

	</summary>
</bill>
