<bill session="112" type="h" number="640" updated="2011-06-04T06:12:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-02-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bone Marrow Failure Disease Research and Treatment Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a National Acquired Bone Marrow Failure Disease Registry, to authorize research on acquired bone marrow failure diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2011-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2011-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2011-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2011-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2011-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412327" joined="2011-06-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2011-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2011-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2011-04-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2011-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-06-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2011-06-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-02-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-18"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
		<term name="Health care quality"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
		<term name="Minority health"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/2011--Introduced.
Bone Marrow Failure Disease Research and Treatment Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) develop a system to collect data on acquired bone marrow failure diseases, (2) establish the National Acquired Bone Marrow Failure Disease Registry, and (3) establish the Advisory Committee on Acquired Bone Marrow Failure Diseases to provide recommendations to the Secretary on the Registry. Allows the Secretary, acting through the Director, to award grants to, and enter to contracts and cooperative agreements with, public or private nonprofit entities for the management of the Registry. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, to conduct pilot studies to determine which environmental factors may cause acquired bone marrow failure diseases. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health, to: (1) establish outreach and information programs targeted to minority populations affected by such diseases; (2) undertake a coordinated outreach effort to connect Hispanic, Asian American, and Pacific Islander communities with comprehensive services focused on treatment of, and information about, such diseases; and (3) awards grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, entities to perform research on such diseases. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), to award grants to entities to improve diagnostic practices and quality of care with respect to patients with such diseases.

	</summary>
</bill>
