<bill session="112" type="h" number="658" updated="2011-05-10T06:10:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-07">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote2 datetime="2011-04-07" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-02-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FAA Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">FAA Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">FAA Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Airport and Airway Trust Fund Financing Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Aviation Research and Development Reauthorization Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">FAA Air Transportation Modernization and Safety Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Dale Long Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Orphan Earmarks Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Volunteer Pilot Protection Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the Federal Aviation Administration for fiscal years 2011 through 2014, to streamline programs, create efficiencies, reduce waste, and improve aviation safety and capacity, to provide stable funding for the national aviation system, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400273"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412403" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412469" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400158" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412464" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412393" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412466" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412427" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412422" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412482" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412454" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412463" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412426" joined="2011-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412408" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412447" joined="2011-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412445" joined="2011-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412441" joined="2011-02-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-02-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-16"><committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-02-16"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 25.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-03-10T19:30:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 112-29, Part I.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-10"><text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology for a period ending not later than March 23, 2011 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(p), rule X.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-10"><text>Referred jointly and sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than March 23, 2011 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l), rule X.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-16T16:18:00-04:00"><text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Transportation, H. Rept. 112-29, Part II.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-23T09:08:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-23T09:09:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="19" datetime="2011-03-23T09:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-03-30T18:19:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 189 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 658 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of the Rules Committee Print dated March 22, 2011.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:45:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 189 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:55:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 189.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2130-2198, H2198-2212"/><reference label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute" ref="CR H2141-2170"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:55:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 658 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of the Rules Committee Print dated March 22, 2011.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:57:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 189 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:57:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jo Ann Emerson to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T14:58:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 658.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mica amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:24:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mica amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rahall demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:25:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waters amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pierluisi amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hirono amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Neugebauer amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LoBiondo amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T16:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:10:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:21:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:21:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hirono amendment no.10.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:30:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hirono amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Hirono demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Miller (MI) amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Woodall amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pierluisi amendment no. 14.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T17:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schweikert amendment no. 15.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Richardson amendment no. 16.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Capuano amendment no. 17.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:17:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Capuano amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Capuano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gingrey amendment no. 18.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:25:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gingrey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Costello demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T18:26:00-04:00"><text>UNFINIHSED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Woodall moved that the Committee now rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:12:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 658 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:15:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2198-2212"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:15:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (MO) amendment no. 19.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sessions amendment no. 20.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:32:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Sessions amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaTourette amendment no. 21.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:44:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaTorette amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Mica demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (MO) amendment no. 22.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:54:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment no. 23.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T19:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shuster amendment no. 24.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:06:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shuster amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rahall demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of the adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:07:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore (WI) amendment no. 25.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (MO) amendment no. 26.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:15:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pearce amendment no. 27.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:23:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pearce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rahall demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment no. 29.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:34:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schiff amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Schiff demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Matheson amendment no. 30.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:41:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schiff amendment no. 31.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 189, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore (WI) amendment no. 32.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:53:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Mica moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:53:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31T20:53:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 658 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T11:12:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2232-2237"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T11:12:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:06:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 658.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:07:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2235"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:07:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:08:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Sanchez, Loretta moved to recommit with instructions to Transportation.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2235-2237"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H2235"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Loretta Sanchez motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding Title XIII- Security of Highest-Risk Airline Passenger Flights. A point of order was reserved, but was subsequently removed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:17:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2236"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:33:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 184 - 235 (Roll no. 219).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="220" datetime="2011-04-01T12:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 223 - 196 (Roll no. 220).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-04-01T12:39:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-04"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S2285"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 223 amended, pursuant to the order of 2/17/2011.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2011-04-07" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Rockefeller; Boxer; Nelson FL; Cantwell; Hutchison; Ensign; DeMint.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S2285"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Senate requests a conference. Appoints conferees. Baucus; Hatch. from the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>See also S. 223.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-08"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-03"><text>Senator(s) Ensign removed as conferee(s).</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-05"><text>Senate appointed conferee(s) Isakson.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-09"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="112" type="hr" number="189" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="223" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="223" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
		<term name="Aviation and airports"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fires"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
		<term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
		<term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
		<term name="Lighting and heating"/>
		<term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
		<term name="Marshall Islands"/>
		<term name="Maryland"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Micronesia"/>
		<term name="Military facilities and property"/>
		<term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
		<term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
		<term name="Motor fuels"/>
		<term name="Music"/>
		<term name="Noise pollution"/>
		<term name="Oceania"/>
		<term name="Palau"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
		<term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Transportation employees"/>
		<term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
		<term name="User charges and fees"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="Worker safety and health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h210"/>
		<amendment number="h211"/>
		<amendment number="h212"/>
		<amendment number="h213"/>
		<amendment number="h214"/>
		<amendment number="h215"/>
		<amendment number="h216"/>
		<amendment number="h217"/>
		<amendment number="h218"/>
		<amendment number="h219"/>
		<amendment number="h220"/>
		<amendment number="h221"/>
		<amendment number="h222"/>
		<amendment number="h223"/>
		<amendment number="h224"/>
		<amendment number="h225"/>
		<amendment number="h226"/>
		<amendment number="h227"/>
		<amendment number="h228"/>
		<amendment number="h229"/>
		<amendment number="h230"/>
		<amendment number="h231"/>
		<amendment number="h232"/>
		<amendment number="h233"/>
		<amendment number="h234"/>
		<amendment number="h235"/>
		<amendment number="h236"/>
		<amendment number="h237"/>
		<amendment number="h238"/>
		<amendment number="h239"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/11/2011--Introduced.
FAA Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2011 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2014 for: (1) airport planning and development and noise compatibility planning programs, (2) Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) air navigation facilities and equipment, (3) FAA operations, and (4) administrative expenses for certain airport programs. Converts to permanent the pilot program for passenger facility charges (PFCs) at nonhub airports. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish a pilot program to authorize, at up to five airports, a PFC to finance the eligible cost of an intermodal ground access project. Directs the Comptroller General to study an alternative means to collect PFCs without their inclusion in the price of an airline ticket. Revises requirements for establishment and adjustment of user fees for FAA services. Directs the FAA Administrator to p rescribe certain registration, certification, and other specified fees. Revises airport improvement program (AIP) requirements. Allows a general aviation airport sponsor, without federal sanction, to enter into a through-the-fence agreement granting a person owning residential real property adjacent to the airport access to the airfield for the person's aircraft or an aircraft the person has authorized. Repeals the prohibition against approval of any Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority application: (1) for an airport development project grant; or (2) to impose a PFC. Requires the FAA Administrator to appoint a Chief NextGen Officer to implement all Next Generation Air Transportation System (NextGen) programs. Directs the DOT Inspector General to review the award and oversight of FAA contracts to provide automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast (ADS-B) services for the national airspace system. Requires the FAA Administrator, after an assessment of leases for critical FAA facility sites located near wind farms or areas suitable for their construction, and following a Comptroller General evaluation of the impact of wind farms on implementation of the NextGen System, to issue guidelines for the construction of such wind farms. Requires the FAA Administrator to monitor the noise impacts of the New York/New Jersey/Philadelphia Metropolitan Area Airspace Redesign. Directs the FAA Administrator to: (1) develop a strategic runway safety plan, as well as a plan for the installation of systems to alert controllers or flight crew members of potential runway incursions; (2) study flight attendant fatigue; and (3) review off-airport, low-altitude aircraft weather observation technologies. Directs the FAA Administrator to conduct a rulemaking proceeding to improve the safety of flight crewmembers, medical personnel, and passengers onboard helicopters providing helicopter air ambulance services. Prohibits flight crewmembers from using a personal wireless communications device or laptop computer while at a duty station on a flight while an aircraft is being operated. Directs the FAA Administrator to establish and implement a safety assessment system for foreign repair stations that perform maintenance on U.S. aircraft. Requires the Secretary to develop a plan for the safe integration of commercial unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system. Establishes in the FAA an Aviation Safety Whistleblower Investigation Office. Directs the FAA Administrator to initiate rulemaking proceedings regarding duty periods and flight time limitations for flight crew members. Revises requirements and authorizes funding through FY2013 for the Essential Air Service (EAS) program. Authorizes funding for FY2014 and each fiscal year thereafter for EAS in Alaska and Hawaii. Repeals the EAS Local Participation Program. Terminates the EAS program (except in Alaska and Hawaii) on October 1, 2013. Increases from 24 to 34 the number of slots exempt from specified requirements and prohibitions concerning operation of an aircraft nonstop between Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport and another airport more than 1,250 statute miles away (Perimeter Rule limit). Requires certain air carriers and airport operators to submit for the Secretary's approval emergency contingency plans for passenger service during grounded aircraft flight delays. Directs the Secretary to notify the public of the DOT's: (1) consumer complaints hotline telephone number; and (2) Aviation Consumer Protection Division website. Expresses the sense of Congress urging all U.S. commercial air carriers to reduce air fares and eliminate certain fees or charges for members of the Armed Forces. Directs the DOT Inspector General to review air carrier flight delays, cancellations, and associated causes since 2000. Directs the Secretary to develop an expedited and coordinated environmental review process for NextGen environmental efficiency projects. Prohibits operating certain aircraft weighing 75,000 pounds or less that do not comply with stage 3 noise levels. Directs the Secretary to establish an aircraft departure queue management pilot program. Authorizes the FAA Administrator to implement practices for the incorporation of energy-efficient measures in the construction and renovation of FAA air traffic control facilities. Revises FAA personnel management system requirements with respect to the mediation, alternative resolution, and binding arbitration of disputes between the FAA Administrator and FAA employees about implementation of proposed changes to the system. Directs the FAA Administrator to assess: (1) FAA's technical training strategy and improvement plan for airway transportation systems specialists, (2) training programs for FAA air traffic controllers, and (3) conditions of FAA facilities. Directs the FAA Administrator to implement a certain staffing model for FAA aviation safety inspectors. Extends the Secretary's authority to provide insurance and reinsurance against loss or damage arising out of any risk from the operation of a domestic or foreign aircraft. Authorizes the FAA Administrator to access the criminal history records or databases systems of specified federal law enforcement agencies. Directs the FAA Administrator to provide for the realignment of FAA services and facilities to facilitate NextGen air traffic control modernization. Establishes the Aviation Facilities and Services Board. Directs the Comptroller General to study the impact of increases in aviation fuel prices on the Airport and Airway Trust Fund and the aviation industry. Amends the Railway Labor Act to grant the DOT Inspector General the authority to review National Mediation Board operations to determine compliance with federal laws, rules, and regulations. Renames space flight participants in commercial space transportation space flight passengers.

	</summary>
</bill>
