<bill session="112" type="h" number="891" updated="2011-06-04T06:13:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medication Therapy Management Benefits Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to promote medication therapy management under the Medicare part D prescription drug program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400659"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412253" joined="2011-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2011-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2011-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2011-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2011-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2011-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2011-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2011-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2011-05-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2011-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2011-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412401" joined="2011-03-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-03"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-08"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health care quality"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Performance measurement"/>
		<term name="Prescription drugs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/2011--Introduced.
Medication Therapy Management Benefits Act of 2011 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require that the annual comprehensive medication review include creation of a personal medication record and a recommended medication action plan in consultation with the individual and the prescriber. Requires medication therapy management (MTM) services to include targeted medication reviews furnished person-to-person by a licensed pharmacist offered at least once every quarter to: (1) assess medication use since the last annual comprehensive medication review, (2) monitor unresolved issues, or (3) identify problems with new drug therapies or if the individual has experienced a transition in care. Increases the number of diseases and conditions for which beneficiaries may be targeted for medication therapy management (MTM) services. Requires a prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor to identify a process, subject to approval by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), that allows licensed pharmacists or other qualified providers to identify potential enrollees for MTM interventions where such individuals are not targeted beneficiaries or are not otherwise offered MTM services. Requires any MTM program to offer both comprehensive and targeted medication reviews to individuals dually eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid (under SSA title XIX), regardless of whether they are MTM-targeted beneficiaries. Requires a PDP sponsor to offer any willing pharmacy in its network the ability to provide MTM services. Requires the PDP sponsor to reimburse pharmacists and other entities furnishing MTM services based on the resources used and the time required to provide such services. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish measures and standards for data collection by PDP sponsors to evaluate performance of pharmacies and other entities in furnishing MTM services; and (2) support the continued development and refinement of performance measures. Provides pharmacies and other entities that furnish MTM services with additional incentive payments based on their performance in meeting quality measures established under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
