<bill session="112" type="h" number="944" updated="2011-05-06T06:14:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-03-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate an unused lighthouse reservation, provide management consistency by incorporating the rocks and small islands along the coast of Orange County, California, into the California Coastal National Monument managed by the Bureau of Land Management, and meet the original Congressional intent of preserving Orange County's rocks and small islands, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-10"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
		<term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
		<term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/2011--Introduced.
Removes the temporary reservation for park, scenic, or other public purposes of certain rocks, pinnacles, reefs, and islands in the Pacific Ocean within a mile of the coast of Orange County, California. Makes such rocks, pinnacles, reefs, and islands part of the California Coastal National Monument and requires that they be administered as part of the Monument. Repeals the lighthouse reservation with respect to the San Juan and San Mateo Rocks and the two rocks in the vicinity of Laguna Beach, off the coast of Orange County.

	</summary>
</bill>
