<bill session="112" type="s" number="1065" updated="2011-06-14T06:31:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-25">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Blackfoot River Land Settlement Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to settle land claims within the Fort Hall Reservation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300030"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412322" joined="2011-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-05-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Indian claims"/>
		<term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/2011--Introduced.
Blackfoot River Land Settlement Act of 2011 - Extinguishes all claims and all right, title, and interest in and to specified Indian and non-Indian land as part of the settlement of disputes within the Fort Hall Indian Reservation of the Shoshone and Bannock Indian Tribes in Idaho resulting from the realignment of the Blackfoot River by the Corps of Engineers in 1964. Requires the non-Indian land to be held in trust for the Tribes. Transfers the Indian land to Blackfoot River Flood Control District No. 7 for conveyance to the non-Indians acquiring Indian land. Establishes a tribal trust fund account from which amounts shall be distributed to the Tribes, which they may use for activities related to: (1) construction of a natural resources facility, (2) water resources needs, (3) economic development, and (4) land acquisition. Establishes an allottee trust account into which amounts shall be deposited into individual Indian money accounts for the allottees. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to pay to the Tribes and the non-Indian landowners such attorney fees as are approved by them. Sets a limit on the total amount of attorney fees that the Secretary may pay. 
	</summary>
</bill>
