<bill session="112" type="s" number="223" updated="2011-04-08T06:17:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-02-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="2011-02-17" where="s" result="pass" how="roll" roll="25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FAA Air Transportation Modernization and Safety Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">FAA Air Transportation Modernization and Safety Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Dale Long Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Orphan Earmarks Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Volunteer Pilot Protection Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the air traffic control system, improve the safety, reliability, and availability of transportation by air in the United States, provide modernization of the air traffic control system, reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-01-27"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-01-28"><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 5 under authority of the order of the Senate of 01/27/2011.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-01"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S377-405"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-02"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S434-477"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-03"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S501-509, S531-538"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-07"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S586-596"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-08"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S622-628"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-14"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S653-656, S659-663, S670-673, S674-676, S677"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-15"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S709-715, S715-727, S731-735, S738-739"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-15"><text>Cloture motion on the bill presented in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S738-739"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S738-739"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-16"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S768-773, S777-778, S780-783"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S809-811, S814-816, S818-820, S823-835"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>Cloture invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 2. Record Vote Number: 20.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S819, "/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>The bill was read the third time.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="25" datetime="2011-02-17" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 87 - 8. Record Vote Number: 25. (text: CR 2/28/2011 S980-1021)</text></vote>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>Ordered held at desk by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 658, pursuant to the order of 2/17/2011, as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-07"><text>See also H.R. 658.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="658" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="658" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="385" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
		<term name="Aviation and airports"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Climate change"/>
		<term name="Coal"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
		<term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
		<term name="Energy prices"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Labor standards"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Military facilities and property"/>
		<term name="Motor fuels"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="New Jersey"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="New York State"/>
		<term name="Noise pollution"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania"/>
		<term name="Personnel records"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Real estate business"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
		<term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
		<term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
		<term name="Transportation employees"/>
		<term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Worker safety and health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s3"/>
		<amendment number="s4"/>
		<amendment number="s5"/>
		<amendment number="s6"/>
		<amendment number="s7"/>
		<amendment number="s8"/>
		<amendment number="s9"/>
		<amendment number="s10"/>
		<amendment number="s11"/>
		<amendment number="s12"/>
		<amendment number="s13"/>
		<amendment number="s14"/>
		<amendment number="s15"/>
		<amendment number="s16"/>
		<amendment number="s17"/>
		<amendment number="s18"/>
		<amendment number="s19"/>
		<amendment number="s20"/>
		<amendment number="s21"/>
		<amendment number="s22"/>
		<amendment number="s23"/>
		<amendment number="s24"/>
		<amendment number="s25"/>
		<amendment number="s26"/>
		<amendment number="s27"/>
		<amendment number="s28"/>
		<amendment number="s29"/>
		<amendment number="s30"/>
		<amendment number="s31"/>
		<amendment number="s32"/>
		<amendment number="s33"/>
		<amendment number="s34"/>
		<amendment number="s35"/>
		<amendment number="s36"/>
		<amendment number="s37"/>
		<amendment number="s38"/>
		<amendment number="s39"/>
		<amendment number="s40"/>
		<amendment number="s41"/>
		<amendment number="s42"/>
		<amendment number="s43"/>
		<amendment number="s44"/>
		<amendment number="s45"/>
		<amendment number="s46"/>
		<amendment number="s47"/>
		<amendment number="s48"/>
		<amendment number="s49"/>
		<amendment number="s50"/>
		<amendment number="s51"/>
		<amendment number="s52"/>
		<amendment number="s53"/>
		<amendment number="s54"/>
		<amendment number="s55"/>
		<amendment number="s56"/>
		<amendment number="s57"/>
		<amendment number="s58"/>
		<amendment number="s59"/>
		<amendment number="s60"/>
		<amendment number="s61"/>
		<amendment number="s62"/>
		<amendment number="s63"/>
		<amendment number="s64"/>
		<amendment number="s65"/>
		<amendment number="s66"/>
		<amendment number="s67"/>
		<amendment number="s68"/>
		<amendment number="s69"/>
		<amendment number="s70"/>
		<amendment number="s71"/>
		<amendment number="s72"/>
		<amendment number="s73"/>
		<amendment number="s74"/>
		<amendment number="s75"/>
		<amendment number="s76"/>
		<amendment number="s77"/>
		<amendment number="s78"/>
		<amendment number="s79"/>
		<amendment number="s80"/>
		<amendment number="s81"/>
		<amendment number="s82"/>
		<amendment number="s83"/>
		<amendment number="s84"/>
		<amendment number="s85"/>
		<amendment number="s86"/>
		<amendment number="s87"/>
		<amendment number="s88"/>
		<amendment number="s89"/>
		<amendment number="s91"/>
		<amendment number="s92"/>
		<amendment number="s93"/>
		<amendment number="s94"/>
		<amendment number="s95"/>
		<amendment number="s96"/>
		<amendment number="s97"/>
		<amendment number="s98"/>
		<amendment number="s99"/>
		<amendment number="s100"/>
		<amendment number="s101"/>
		<amendment number="s102"/>
		<amendment number="s103"/>
		<amendment number="s104"/>
		<amendment number="s105"/>
		<amendment number="s106"/>
		<amendment number="s107"/>
		<amendment number="s108"/>
		<amendment number="s109"/>
		<amendment number="s110"/>
		<amendment number="s111"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/2011--Introduced.
FAA Air Transportation Modernization and Safety Improvement Act - Reduces the authorization of appropriations for FY2010 for Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) operations. Increases the authorization of appropriations for FY2010 for: (1) FAA air navigation facilities and equipment, (2) civil aviation research and development, and (3) airport planning and development and noise compatibility planning and programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY2011 for: (1) FAA operations, (2) FAA air navigation facilities and equipment, (3) civil aviation research and development, (4) airport planning and development and noise compatibility planning and programs, and (5) certain other aviation programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2011 for administrative expenses for certain airport programs. Revises procedural requirements for imposition of aircraft passenger facility charges (PFCs). Establishes an alternative PFC collection pilot program. Revises the federal share of costs for certain airport improvement projects. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to establish a pilot program for up to three states to participate in the airport improvement program (AIP) state block grant program. Directs the Secretary to establish a pilot program to carry out up to six environmental mitigation demonstration projects at public-use airports. Directs the FAA Administrator to establish an airport sustainability working group. Establishes: (1) an Air Traffic Control Modernization Oversight Board, and (2) the position of Chief NextGen Officer who shall implement all Next Generation Air Transportation System (NextGen) programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT). Requires the FAA Administrator to: (1) consider whether the provision of NextGen air traffic services by nongovernment providers would promote safety and improve efficiency of the National Airspace System, and (2) make recommendations for the realignment of FAA services and facilities to assist in the transition to next generation facilities. Revises FAA personnel management system requirements with respect to the mediation, alternative resolution, and binding arbitration of disputes between the FAA Administrator and FAA employees about implementation of proposed changes to the system. Requires the FAA Administrator to report on navigation performance and area navigation operations and procedures required to maximize the efficiency and capacity of NextGen commercial operations at 35 Operational Evolution Partnership airports. Requires the FAA Administrator to report to Congress on the program and schedule for integrating automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast (ADS-B) technology into the National Airspace System. Requires the FAA Administrator to: (1) establish and track National Airspace System performance metrics, and (2) report to Congress on financing proposals to fully fund the development and implementation of the NextGen system in a manner that does not increase the federal deficit. Requires the FAA Administrator to develop a plan to accelerate the integration of unmanned aerial systems into the National Airspace System. Directs the Air Traffic Organization evaluate the Airport Surface Detection Equipment-Model X program and airport surveillance technologies and associated collaborative surface management software for potential contributions to the NextGen initiative and surface management. Requires the FAA Administrator to establish a process for including FAA employees who are likely to be affected by the deployment of air traffic control modernization projects (including NextGen) in the planning, development, and deployment of such projects. Establishes the FAA Task Force on Air Traffic Control Facility Conditions. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with up to five states to establish state ADS-B equipage banks. Directs the FAA Administrator to: (1) provide specified California air traffic control facilities with new air traffic controller training staff and equipment, and (2) report to Congress on the strategy for accelerated implementation of the NextGen operational capabilities produced by the Greener Skies project. Authorizes the FAA Administrator to enter agreements to fund the costs of equipping aircraft for NextGen air traffic control capabilities. Requires air carriers and airport operators to propose for the Secretary's approval contingency plans for passenger service during grounded aircraft flight delays. Directs the Secretary to establish in the DOT: (1) a consumer hotline telephone number for air passenger complaints, and (2) an advisory committee for aviation consumer protection. Prescribes disclosure requirements for sellers of airline tickets. Revises requirements and increases additional funding for the Essential Air Service program. Extends the small community air service development program through FY2011. Establishes an Office of Rural Aviation within the Office of the Secretary. Repeals the Essential Air Service Local Participation Program. Authorizes the use of certain lands in the Las Vegas McCarran International Airport Environs Overlay District for transient lodging and associated facilities. Directs the FAA Administrator to issue a plan to develop a schedule for installation of systems to alert controllers and flight crews to potential runway incursions. Authorizes the FAA Administrator to access the criminal history records or databases systems of specified federal law enforcement agencies. Directs the FAA Administrator to issue regulations limiting the hours of flight and duty time for pilots to address pilot fatigue. Requires helicopter and fixed-wing aircraft certificate holders providing emergency medical services to comply with federal safety operating requirements if there is a medical crew on board, without regard to whether patients are also on board. Directs the FAA Administrator to: (1) establish within the FAA a national review team to conduct periodic, unannounced, random reviews of FAA's oversight of air carriers; (2) conduct a review and evaluation of the FAA's Academy and facility training programs; and (3) develop a plan for the reduction of runway incursions. Establishes in the FAA an Aviation Safety Whistleblower Investigation Office. Directs the FAA Administrator to establish and implement a safety assessment system for foreign repair stations that perform maintenance on U.S. aircraft. Directs the FAA Administrator to establish an electronic pilot records database of pertinent information in FAA, air carrier, and other records (including the National Driver Register) that an air carrier shall access and evaluate before allowing an individual to begin service as a pilot. Requires the FAA Administrator to: (1) develop and implement a plan for reevaluation of flight crew training, testing, and certification regulations; (2) initiate rulemaking proceedings to require part 121 air carriers to establish remedial training programs for certain deficient flightcrew members, flightcrew member mentoring and leadership development programs, and methods for screening flightcrew members for qualifications and experience; (3) issue a final rule to establish safety standards for training programs for flight crew members and aircraft dispatchers; and (4) establish research grant programs to reduce civilian aircraft energy use, emissions, and noise and to develop jet fuel from natural gas, biomass, and other renewable sources, as well as clean coal. Prohibits flightcrew members from using a personal wireless communications device or laptop computer while at a duty station on a flight deck while an aircraft is being operated. Requires air carriers to provide recurring training for flight attendants and gate agents. Directs the FAA Administrator to study air quality in aircraft cabins. Establishes an Advisory Committee on the Future of Aeronautics. Reauthorizes through FY2012 the FAA Center for Excellence for Applied Research and Training in the Use of Advanced Materials in Transport Aircraft. Directs the Secretary to establish a zero emission airport vehicles and infrastructure pilot program. Directs the FAA Administrator to implement a program for research and development of equipment to clean and monitor the engine and auxiliary power unit (APU) bleed air supplied on pressurized aircraft. Extends the Secretary's authority to provide insurance and reinsurance against loss or damage arising out of any risk from the operation of a domestic or foreign aircraft. Prohibits operating certain aircraft weighing 75,000 pounds or less that do not comply with stage 3 noise levels. Directs the FAA Administrator to: (1) establish a pilot program for redevelopment of airport properties; and (2) initiate a study on front line manager staffing requirements for FAA air traffic control facilities. Directs the Comptroller General to study the helicopter and fixed-wing air ambulance industry. Repeals the prohibition against approval of any Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority : (1) for an airport development project grant; or (2) to impose a passenger facility fee. Directs the FAA Administrator to study: (1) aeronautical mobile telemetry services; and (2) aviation industry best practices for flightcrew member pairing, crew resource management techniques, and pilot commuting. Directs the Comptroller General to study airline and intercity passenger rail codeshare arrangements and aviation fuel prices. Directs the Secretary to convey to Clark County, Nevada, all right, title, and interest of specified U.S. public land for development of flood mitigation infrastructure for the Southern Nevada Supplemental Airport. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through FY2013: (1) excise taxes on aviation fuels and air transportation of persons and property; and (2) authority for expenditures from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund. Revises the excise tax on kerosene used in aviation. Establishes within the Airport and Airway Trust Fund a separate Air Traffic Control System Modernization Account, with deposits derived from taxes on aviation-grade kerosene, which shall be available for expenditures relating to the modernization of the air traffic control system. Imposes a surtax on fuel used in aircraft which are part of a fractional ownership program. Prescribes requirements for passenger tax disclosures on airline tickets. Rescinds DOT earmarks, except in certain circumstances, when 90% of an earmark remains available for obligation at the end of the ninth fiscal year after it was first made available.

	</summary>
</bill>
