<bill session="112" type="s" number="398" updated="2011-06-08T06:12:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-12">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-04-12" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-02-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Implementation of National Consensus Appliance Agreements Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to improve energy efficiency of certain appliances and equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412321" joined="2011-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2011-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2011-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2011-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2011-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2011-04-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412323" joined="2011-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2011-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2011-04-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2011-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2011-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-04-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-04-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-04-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2011-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2011-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2011-03-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S890-891)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-02-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S891-904"/></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-10.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-04-12"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-18"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 112-18.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="54" datetime="2011-05-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 54.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="h" number="482" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="112" type="s" number="156" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Connecticut"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Food industry and services"/>
		<term name="Games and hobbies"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Illinois"/>
		<term name="Indiana"/>
		<term name="Iowa"/>
		<term name="Kansas"/>
		<term name="Lighting and heating"/>
		<term name="Maine"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Michigan"/>
		<term name="Minnesota"/>
		<term name="Missouri"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="Nebraska"/>
		<term name="New Hampshire"/>
		<term name="New Jersey"/>
		<term name="New York State"/>
		<term name="North Dakota"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania"/>
		<term name="Rhode Island"/>
		<term name="South Dakota"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
		<term name="Vermont"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water use and supply"/>
		<term name="West Virginia"/>
		<term name="Wisconsin"/>
		<term name="Wyoming"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/17/2011--Introduced.
Implementation of National Consensus Appliance Agreements Act of 2011 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA) to set forth provisions concerning establishing standards for: (1) a minimum level of energy efficiency or a maximum quantity of water use for clothes washers and dishwashers; (2) the seasonal energy efficiency ratio of central air conditioners and central air conditioning heat pumps manufactured on or after January 1, 2015; (3) the annual fuel utilization efficiency of non-weatherized furnaces manufactured on or after May 1, 2013; (4) energy efficiency of GU-24 Base Lamps, high light output double-ended quartz halogen lamps, general service fluorescent lamps, general service incandescent lamps, intermediate base incandescent lamps, candelabra base incandescent lamps, and incandescent reflector lamps; (5) energy efficiency of bottle-type water dispensers and compartment bottle-type water dispensers, commercial hot food holding cabinets, and portable electric spas; (6) energy conservation of refrigerators and freezers manufactured on or after January 1, 2014; (7) minimum energy efficiency ratios of room air conditioners manufactured on or after June 1, 2014; (8) minimum energy efficiency of clothes dryers manufactured on or after January 1, 2015; (9) energy conservation of certain incandescent reflector lamps; (10) energy efficiency of warm air furnaces with an input rating of 225,000 Btu per hour or more and manufactured on or after the date that is one year after this Act's enactment; (11) daily energy consumption of service over the counter, self-contained, medium temperature commercial refrigerators; and (12) nominal full load efficiency of specified electric motors. Requires the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to publish rules that determine whether the Secretary should: (1) establish or amend standards for through-the-wall central air conditioners, through-the-wall central air conditioning heat pumps, and small duct, high velocity systems; (2) amend standards for weatherized furnaces; and (3) initiate a process for establishing minimum energy efficiency standards for video game console energy use.
Amends the Energy Conservation Program for Consumer Products Other Than Automobiles to: (1) revise exceptions from preemption requirements for certain building code requirements; and (2) revise labeling rules for &quot;covered products.&quot; Prohibits the manufacture of general purpose mercury vapor lamps on or after January 1, 2016. Provides that state energy conservation standards that are adopted by January 1, 2015, pursuant to statutory requirements to adopt efficiency standards for reducing outdoor lighting energy use enacted prior to January 31, 2008, will not be preempted by federal standards. Provides that California and Nevada are not precluded from adopting, effective beginning on or after January 1, 2018, standards for general service lamps. Requires the Administrator to determine whether to update the Energy Star criteria for residential refrigerators, refrigerator-freezers, freezers, dishwashers, clothes washers, clothes dryers, and room air conditioners to incorporate smart grid and demand response features.
Requires the Secretary to establish a program concerning increasing awareness of higher efficiency electric motors.

	</summary>
</bill>
