<bill session="112" type="s" number="675" updated="2011-04-08T06:18:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-07">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-04-07" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with Native Hawaiians and to provide a process for the recognition by the United States of the Native Hawaiian governing entity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2011-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-03-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1978-1979)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1979-1984"/></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-04-07"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="112" type="h" number="1250" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
		<term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/30/2011--Introduced.
Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2011 - Establishes the U.S. Office for Native Hawaiian Relations within the Office of the Secretary of the Interior. Establishes the Native Hawaiian Interagency Coordinating Group. Recognizes the right of the qualified Native Hawaiian constituents to reorganize the single Native Hawaiian governing entity to provide for their common welfare and to adopt appropriate organic governing documents. Establishes a Commission to: (1) prepare and maintain a roll of such constituents, and (2) certify that individuals on the roll meet the definition of qualified Native Hawaiian. Outlines the process for the reorganization, which includes forming a Native Hawaiian Interim Governing Council. Reaffirms the special political and legal relationship between the United States and the Native Hawaiian people upon the Secretary's approval of the organic governing documents and the installation of officers elected to the Native Hawaiian governing entity. Extends federal recognition to the governing entity as the representative sovereign governing body of the Native Hawaiian people. Authorizes the United States, upon the reaffirmation of such political and legal relationship, together with the state of Hawaii, to enter into negotiations with the governing entity for an agreement addressing matters that include: (1) land, natural resource, and asset transfers; (2) governing powers and responsibilities; and (3) grievances. Prohibits Native Hawaiians or their governing entity from conducting gaming activities as a matter of claimed inherent authority or under the authority of federal law.

	</summary>
</bill>
