<bill session="112" type="s" number="710" updated="2011-06-08T06:12:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-04-14">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-04-14" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest Establishment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400546"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2011-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2011-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2011-04-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-04-14"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-06-07"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 112-20.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="72" datetime="2011-06-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 72.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Computers and information technology"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
		<term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
		<term name="User charges and fees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/2011--Introduced.
Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest Establishment Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system that may be used by a hazardous waste generator or transporter, an owner or operator of a hazardous waste treatment, storage, recycling, or disposal facility, or any other person that: (1) is required to use a manifest to comply with any federal or state requirement to track the shipment, transportation, and receipt of hazardous waste or other material shipped from the generation site to an off-site facility for treatment, storage, disposal, or recycling; and (2) elects to use the system to complete and transmit an electronic manifest format; or (3) submits to the system for data processing purposes a paper copy of the manifest (or data from such a paper copy). Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) impose service fees on users to pay for developing, operating, maintaining, and upgrading the system, including any costs incurred in collecting and processing data from any paper manifest submitted to the system after the date on which the system enters operation; (2) deposit the fees into the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Fund (established by this Act); and (3) enter into information technology contracts with appropriate entities for the provision of system-related services. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Advisory Board; and (2) carry out this Act in each state unless the state program is fully authorized to do so. Requires a designated facility that receives waste, in cases in which the state in which waste is generated or transported to such facility requires that the waste be tracked through a hazardous waste manifest, to: (1) complete the facility portion of the applicable manifest, (2) sign and date the facility certification, and (3) submit to the system a final copy of the manifest.

	</summary>
</bill>
