<bill session="112" type="s" number="792" updated="2011-06-09T06:14:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-26">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-05-26" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the waiver of certain debts relating to assistance provided to individuals and households since 2005.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2011-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412495" joined="2011-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412494" joined="2011-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="2011-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2011-05-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2394-2395)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-04-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-26"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
		<term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/2011--Introduced.
Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to waive a debt owed to the United States relating to covered assistance (federal assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to individuals and households in relation to a major disaster declared by the President during the period of August 28, 2005-December 31, 2011) if such assistance was distributed based on an error by FEMA. Requires the Administrator to waive a debt owed to the United States relating to covered assistance provided to an individual or household located in an area that the Administrator has identified as having special flood hazards and that is located in a community that does not participate in the national flood insurance program, if the reason for the debt relates to a failure to participate in such program. Prohibits the Administrator from waiving such a debt that involves fraud, the presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the debtor or any party having an interest in the claim.

	</summary>
</bill>
