<bill session="112" type="s" number="968" updated="2011-06-10T06:15:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-05-26">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="2011-05-26" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Real Online Threats to Economic Creativity and Theft of Intellectual Property Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT IP Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Preventing Real Online Threats to Economic Creativity and Theft of Intellectual Property Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">PROTECT IP Act of 2011</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent online threats to economic creativity and theft of intellectual property, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412390" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400034" joined="2011-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2011-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2011-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2011-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412378" joined="2011-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-05-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2936-2937)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-05-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced in Senate" ref="CR S2937-2940"/></action>
		<calendar datetime="2011-05-26"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="2011-05-26"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="70" datetime="2011-05-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 70.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
		<term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Internet and video services"/>
		<term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
		<term name="Prescription drugs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/2011--Introduced.
Preventing Real Online Threats to Economic Creativity and Theft of Intellectual Property Act of 2011 or the PROTECT IP Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Attorney General (AG) or an intellectual property right owner harmed by an Internet site dedicated to infringing activities (ISDIA) to commence an action against: (1) a registrant of an ISDIA's domain name, or (2) an owner or operator of an ISDIA accessed through a domain name. Allows the AG to commence actions against such individuals associated with nondomestic domain names (NDN). Permits the AG, if the specified individuals are unable to be found or have no address within a U.S. judicial district, to commence in rem actions (against domain names themselves, in lieu of individuals) against such domain names. Defines ISDIA as a site that: (1) has no significant use other than engaging in or facilitating copyright infringement, circumventing technology controlling access to copyrighted works, or selling or promoting counterfeit goods or services; or (2) is designed, operated, or marketed and used to engage in such activities. Allows the court, upon application by the relevant plaintiff, to issue temporary restraining orders or injunctions against further ISDIA activity under specified circumstances. Sets forth the preventative measures to be taken, upon being served with a court order, by: (1) operators of nonauthoritative domain name system servers, financial transaction providers (FTPs), Internet advertising services (IASs), and information location tools (ILTs) with respect to NDNs; or (2) FTPs and IASs with respect to domain names other than NDNs. Provides immunity from liability for: (1) FTPs or IASs voluntarily taking certain preventative actions against ISDIAs, and (2) domain name registries, FTPs, ILTs, or IASs withholding services from infringing sites that endanger public health by distributing prescription medication that is counterfeit, adulterated, misbranded, or without a valid prescription.

	</summary>
</bill>
