<bill session="112" type="sr" number="80" updated="2011-05-20T06:10:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="2011-03-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="2011-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the Government of Iran for its state-sponsored persecution of its Baha'i minority and its continued violation of the International Covenants on Human Rights.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2011-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2011-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2011-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2011-04-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2011-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2011-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412491" joined="2011-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412326" joined="2011-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2011-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2011-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2011-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412325" joined="2011-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412490" joined="2011-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412320" joined="2011-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2011-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2011-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="2011-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1062)</text></action>
		<action datetime="2011-03-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1062"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="112" type="hr" number="134" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International law and treaties"/>
		<term name="Iran"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Sanctions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2011--Introduced.
Condemns the government of Iran for its state-sponsored persecution of its Baha'i minority and its continued violation of the International Covenants on Human Rights. Calls on the government of Iran to release seven specified imprisoned Baha'i leaders and all other prisoners held on account of their religion, including: Mrs. Fariba Kamalabadi, Mr. Jamaloddin Khanjani, Mr. Afif Naeimi, Mr. Saeid Rezaie, Mr. Behrouz Tavakkoli, Mrs. Mahvash Sabet, Mr. Vahid Tizfahm, Ms. Raha Sabet, and Mr. Navid Khanjani. Calls on the President and Secretary of State, in cooperation with the international community, to condemn Iran's continued violation of human rights and demand the release of prisoners held on account of their religion, including the above-named individuals. Urges the President and Secretary to utilize all available measures, such as those available under the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 and Executive Order 13553, to sanction Iranian government officials and other individuals directly responsible for human rights violations in Iran, including against the Baha'i community.

	</summary>
</bill>
